Andrew M. Kent

CONTACT Information RESEARCH INTERESTS I'm interested in developing programming language based techniques that help developers design and build robust software in real world settings. In particular I hope to increase the accessibility and effectiveness of verification techniques by exploring their gradual application.

EDUCATION

Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Ph.D. Student, Computer Science, May 2014 - Present

• Advisor: Sam Tobin-Hochstadt

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah USA

B.S., Computer Science, August 2013

Honors and Awards Graduated magna cum laude from Brigham Young University.

Awarded NASA Space Grant Consortium Fellowship (Fall 2013 – Winter 2014)

Top graduate in multi-service military Intermediate Communications Signals Analysis course (Corry Station Naval Technical Training Center, Florida, April – August 2007)

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana USA

Graduate Research Assistant

May 2014 - Present

Investigating type-based program verification, evaluating gradual typing applications in mainstream languages, and developing techniques to bring dependent types to dynamically typed languages. Advised by Sam Tobin-Hochstadt.

 $Assistant\ Instructor$

January 2017 - Present

CSCI-B 401 Fundamentals of Computing Theory

Assisting with instruction and grading for undergraduate level course on the theory of computation.

Assistant Instructor

January – May 2016

CSCI-B 522 Programming Language Foundations

Assisted with instruction and grading for graduate level programming language theory course. Shared responsibility for lectures, exams, homework assignments, and grades.

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah USA

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2013 – April 2014

Investigated the formalization of security protocol analysis techniques (Strand Spaces) utilizing the Coq proof assistant to create a verified basis for accessible, automated protocol analysis techniques. Advised by Jay McCarthy.

Teaching Assistant

August 2013 – April 2014

CS-330 Concepts of Programming Languages

Held regular office hours and assisted in teaching programming language concepts.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May - September 2011

Developed method for automatically generating historical social networks from source documents to aid historical research. Advised by William Berret and Tom Sederberg.

PUBLICATIONS

Occurrence Typing Modulo Theories, with David Kempe and Sam Tobin-Hochstadt, *Proc.* 37th ACM Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI), 2016.

Design and Evaluation of Gradual Typing in Python, with Michael M. Vitousek, Jeremy G. Siek, and Jim Baker, *Proc.* 10th ACM Symposium on Dynamic Languages (DLS), 2014.

Linking the Past: Discovering Historical Social Networks from Documents and Linking to a Genealogical Database, with Douglas J. Kennard and William A. Barrett, *Proc.* 1st Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing (HIP), 2011.

Talks

Practical Dependently Typed Racket, RacketCon 2015, St. Louis, MO, USA.

Adding Practical Dependent Types to Typed Racket, Scripts to Programs Workshop 2015, Prague, Czech Republic.

Professional Experience

Microsoft Corporation, Redmond, Washington USA

Software Development Engineer Intern

May 2012 - August 2012

Explored optimizations and improvements for Microsoft OneNote during a summer internship, receiving a full-time offer for employment upon completion.

United States Marine Corps, Camp Pendleton, California USA

Signals Intelligence Analyst

November 2005 – August 2010

Provided detailed signals intelligence analysis and reporting in support combat operations in the Al Anbar province of Iraq during two separate deployments. Additionally, trained and led a team of six signals intelligence analysts during the second deployment to Iraq.

COMMUNITY

Cub Master

December 2014 – Present

Help organize combined scouting activities for youth ages 8-11.

 $Interfaith\ Winter\ Shelter\ Volunteer$

January 2016 - Present

Evening shift volunteer for at a low-barrier winter homeless shelter.